准备好了吗  孩子们
Are you ready, kids?
好了船长
Aye aye, captain
我听不见
I can't hear you
好了船长
Aye aye, captain
是谁住在深海的大菠萝里
Who lives in a pineapple under the sea?
海绵宝宝
SpongeBob SquarePants
方方黄黄伸缩自如
Absorbent and yellow and porous is he
海绵宝宝
SpongeBob SquarePants
如果四处探险是你的愿望
If nautical nonsense be something you wish
海绵宝宝
SpongeBob SquarePants
那就敲敲甲板让大鱼开路
Then drop on the deck and flop like a fish
海绵宝宝
SpongeBob SquarePants
准备
Ready
海绵宝宝
SpongeBob SquarePants
肮脏泡泡鱼
编剧
翻译: 1440kHz
分镜总监
指导总监
统筹
监制
本字幕仅限学习交流
严禁用于商业用途
超棒漫画店
派大星你看
Look, Patrick
肮脏泡泡集换卡
Dirty Bubble trading cards
世上最稀有的集换卡
The rarest trading cards in existence
肮脏泡泡卡
真的是用
肮脏泡泡的脏污做的
我要发动先抢先得远古仪式
I invoke the ancient rite of dibs
还真没毛病
Can't argue with that
出口
很好  我的肮脏泡泡收藏集
Yes, my collection of Dirty Bubblobilia
总算要完成了
will finally be complete
恭喜你
Congratulations
你是这里最酷的酷哥
You're the coolest guy here
旧物的灰味最香了
There's nothing like the smell of vintage dust
海霸王
Bubble Bass
你又去逛那家发霉漫画店了吗
Have you been in that musty comic shop again?
给我上楼洗澡
You march yourself upstairs and take your bath
既来之则安之吧
While we're here, why not make the most of it?
来点官方正品肮脏泡泡浴
A little official Dirty Bubble bubble bath
卡放哪去了
Now, where are those cards?
还附赠一根肮脏泡泡糖
They come with a stick of Dirty Bubble bubble gum
天啊  这股怀旧味
Oh, dear, the nostalgic flavor
害我有些消化不良了
has given me a case of dyspepsia
好
Yes
我自由了
I'm free
肮脏泡泡
The Dirty Bubble
你嚼了那个硬皮泡泡糖  解救了我
You chewing that crusty gum has freed me
让我逃出了美人鱼战士的泡泡糖牢笼
from Mermaid Man's bubblegum trap
你叫什么名字  小胖墩
What's your name, my bulbous buddy?
泡泡鱼
Bubble Bass
新跟班叫这个名字正好
What a perfect name for my new sidekick
跟班当然要跟到我身体里
Or should I say, inside kick
放我出去
Let me out
作为解救我的回报
As a reward for releasing me
你现在是我的同伙了
you're my new partner in crime
怎么回
What's going on in--
海霸王
Bubble Bass
你比洗澡之前还脏
You're even filthier than before you took a bath
不怪我  老妈
It's not my fault, Mother
我被困在这个肮脏罪犯里了
I'm trapped inside this foul felon
我可不愿意挑拨巨婴跟他妈
I hate to come between a man child and his mama
但现在该脏还得脏
but it's time to grime
肮脏
摆脱这身黏液可得要大半辈子
It'll take forever to get out of this goop
对不起  老妈
I'm sorry, Mother
来办事吧
OK, let's get busy now
求你了
Please
别附在我身上了
Remove yourself from my person
很抱歉  兄弟
Sorry, fella
你来掩护我犯罪正好
but you'll be the perfect cover for my crimes
别动什么歪点子
And don't get any funny ideas
肮脏泡泡现在可是在支配着你呢
The Dirty Bubble is in control now
体力活动
Physical activity?
不要
No
那种事情不要啊
Anything but that
快做点什么啊
Please, do something
既然你知道谁是老大了
Now that you know who's boss
就来肮脏地干一票吧
let's start our grime spree
第一航海银行
我好久都没抢劫过银行了
I haven't bagged a bank in ages
都不许动
Nobody move
我要来熏爆大家
This is a stink up
恶心
Disgusting
可能得稍微
We may need to do a little--
洗钱一下了
money laundering
犯罪还真有回报
I guess crime does pay
不许动  肮脏罪犯
Freeze, you filthy felon
感谢赞美  警官
Thanks for the compliment, Officer
不要
No
污秽
我倒有点喜欢上了这场小小的犯罪
I'm beginning to enjoy this little felonious--
远行
excursion
不过得吃点东西
I need sustenance, though
我正好知道犯什么罪能填饱肚子
I know the perfect crime to fill our bellies
我就喜欢你的胆识
I like your moxie
给我瞧瞧你的本事  小跟班
Show me what you got, Sidekick
蟹堡王
艺术
马上把蟹黄堡全都端出来
Give me all your Krabby Patties post haste
你给我穿好衣服
Keep your shirt on--
穿好黏液
goop on
蟹黄堡全都要吗
All our Krabby Patties?
我来服务这位可爱客人  章鱼哥先生
I'll handle this charming customer, Mr. Squidward
海绵宝宝
SpongeBob
马上来一份蟹堡全家桶
We need a Krabby Bucket, pronto
上菜了
Order up
好爱你扮的肮脏泡泡  海霸王
Love the Dirty Bubble cosplay, Bubble Bass
好啊
Oh, yes
吃了这顿  精神到不能再精神了
This greasy grub is most invigorating
原来真的是肮脏泡泡
The real Dirty Bubble?
刚刚的餐点很好吃
It was a delightful repast
但恐怕我还是要退钱
But I'm afraid I still require a refund
我的钱
Me money
海霸王  滚出我家蟹堡王
Bubble Bass, get out of me restaurant
但得先把钱还给我
But first, give me me money back
抱歉  我们不会滚
Sorry, we won't be leaving--
先抢个劫再说
Until we're done thieving
不好了
Oh, no
派大星
Patrick
海绵宝宝
SpongeBob
我还要在这吃饭呢
I'm trying to eat here
我小跟班也是
So is my sidekick
再送你一个  同伙
Here's another one, partner
找自个的蟹黄堡吸去吧
Find your own patty to suck on
等等
Wait
别走
Don't go
快
Quick
进来
Get in
要是美人鱼战士在这就好了
If only Mermaid Man were here
我们应该可以自己应付
I think we can handle this ourselves
一起扎破泡泡吧
Let's go pop that bubble
住手  肮脏泡泡
Stop right there, Dirty Bubble
你们这是装成什么了
What are you supposed to be?
致敬美人鱼战士的乐队吗
A Mermaid Man tribute band?
来问候问候海绵战士
Say hello to Mermaid-Pants
小气队长
Captain Tightwad
负能量怪医
Dr. Negative
还有还行蓝孩
And Affordable Car
你是不是想说海星男孩
Don't you mean "Barnacle Star?"
就那么说
What he said
海星飞镖
Sea star swipe
飞镖
吃我硬币夹
Feel my penny pinch
夹
小心蟹爪  老螃蟹
Watch the claws, Crabby
不要不要
No, no, no, no
请洗鳍
消毒
尝尝我的负能量感应
Try my negative vibes
感应
你的负能量敌不过我的鄙视
Your negativity is no match for my disdain
谁理你
真扫兴
What a bummer
扫兴
你是我们最后的希望了  海星男孩
You're our last hope, Barnacle Star
抱歉  我什么招都没有
Sorry, I got nothing
没有
黏糊糊
既然打败那些假冒小丑了
Now that those counterfeit clowns are pulverized
接下来要犯什么滔天大罪
what nefarious misdeeds should we commit next?
我的肮脏力量快用完了  同伙
My filthy powers are running low, partner
得充能
I need a recharge
我知道有个好地方
I know the perfect place
可以给你补充肮脏力量
to invigorate your noxious batteries
海之霸
The Chum Bucket
点餐
能给多少桶海霸糊就给多少
Bring out as many buckets of chum as you can
先出钱
Show me the money first
快端上来吧
And keep it coming
当然好啊  先生
Why, certainly, sir
厨房
恶心又好吃
Disgustingly delicious
海之霸卖的食物全裤头村最难吃
The Chum Bucket serves
the foulest fare in Bikini Bottom
好啊
Oh, yeah
我能感受到里面的肮脏力量
I can feel its putrid power
在流经我的泡泡身体
coursing through my bubbly body
很多桶之后
一定要再来
I must have more
382  383
382, 383--
中奖了
Jackpot
中的还是一大桶海霸糊
Or should I say chum-pot?
我的预判好像出了一点点
I may have made a slight--
差错
miscalculation
吃了这么一大口  我天下无敌了
This chubby chow has made me invincible
有剩菜
Leftovers
从现在起
From now on
还是只粉不控制我生活的反派吧
I'll stick to villains who don't control my life
海霸王
Bubble Bass
老妈
Mother
马上回家把澡给我洗完
You come home right this instant and finish your bath
马上来  老妈
Right away, Mother
绵家谢尔顿
编剧
分镜总监
翻译: 1440kHz
指导总监
动画总监
统筹
监制
本字幕仅限学习交流
严禁用于商业用途
好了
There
还不错
Not bad
但我出这步  你会如何应对
But let's see what you think of this move
不好意思  派大星
Excuse me, Patrick
我先接一下
I should get this
喂
Yello?
喂  儿子
Hello, son
你忙吗
Are you busy?
我跟派大星
Well, Patrick and I
倒立跳棋正下得如火如荼呢
are pretty deep into a game of upside-down checkers
不过我向来都有时间陪你和老妈
but I always have time for you and Mom
这么说就好
We're very glad to hear that
因为我们给你准备了个惊喜
because we have a surprise for you
有惊喜
A surprise?
我爱惊喜
I love surprises
可以马上就过来吗
Can you come over right away?
那当然了
You bet
马上见
See you soon
抱歉  派大星
Sorry, Patrick
我得走了
I have to go
不过小蜗可以陪你下完
But Gary can finish the game with you
看来我只剩最后一步棋了
Looks like I only have one move left
牛油果公寓区
疗养社区
老妈好
Hi, Mom
老爸好
Hi, Dad
宝贝儿子好
Hello, darling
我的惊喜一定就在这附近的
My surprise has to be around here somewhere
还真是  儿子
It sure is, Son
准备好看惊喜了吗
Are you ready for it?
在哪
Where is it?
你就站在上面呢
Well, you're standing on it
痞老板
Plankton?
认识一下你的新弟弟  谢尔顿
Meet your new brother, Sheldon
我们今早在大门台阶上发现他的
We found him on our doorstep this morning
他超级可爱
He was just as cute as a button
于是我们做了
And we did
任何正派海绵都会做的事
what any decent sponges would do
马上就收养了这个弃婴
and immediately adopted the little foundling
我是你的新弟弟
I'm your new brother
等一下
Wait a minute
这也
This is--
太棒了
great
我一直都想要一个弟弟
I've always wanted a brother
好  你们两个开心玩
All right, you two boys have fun
好了  海绵宝宝
All right, SpongeBob
听见俩白痴说的话了吧
You heard the dopes
我是说  老爸老妈
I mean, "Mommy" and "Daddy"
我们变兄弟了
We're brothers now
兄弟之间无话不谈
And brothers tell each other everything
尤其会谈蟹黄堡的秘密配方
Especially the Krabby Patty secret formula
没错  痞老板
You're right, Plankton
兄弟之间不留秘密
There's no secrets between brothers
好
Yes
不过我们得先亲近一下
But first, we have to get closer
要像亲兄弟一样  一起做事情
by doing things together, like brothers do
好吧
Fine
首先来一局接球游戏
First up, a little game of catch
等一下  等一下
Hold on, hold on
这手套太大了
This glove is too big
小心
Heads up
来
Here
你来接
Here you go
投得真好  痞老板
Nice throw, Plankton
现在这一球要加点料了
Now here comes one with a little spice on it
别  等下
No, wait
疼啊
It burns
哈罗德
Oh, Harold
看到两个儿子和睦相处  真是高兴啊
it's so nice to see our boys getting along
确实高兴  亲爱的
It really is, dear
接得也差不多了
OK, enough catch
要不现在来分享一下秘密呢
How about we share secrets now?
对不起  兄弟情谊计还没填满呢
Sorry, but we haven't filled
秘密
兄弟情
our brotherly love meter yet
还要再多加深一下兄弟情
We have more bonding to do
而且加深兄弟情最好的方式
And what better way to brotherly bond
就是帮助邻居了
than by helping our neighbors?
屋里的善良小姐一定
I'm sure these nice ladies will
会有家务可以给我们做
have some chores for us to do
好啊
Goody
你们卖的东西我一律不买
Whatever you're selling, I'm not buying
不对  阿姨
No, ma'am
我和我弟在希望
My brother and I were hoping
你还剩了一点家务活
you had some housework that needs doing
你们俩看着就像一对怪东西
You two look like a couple of weirdos
我绝对不让怪东西碰我家东西
And I don't let weirdos touch my stuff
妈
Ma
别闹了
Give it a rest
别理她
Don't mind her
你们可以修剪我们家海草坪
You boys can mow our kelp lawn
割草机就放在轮胎旁边
Mower's out by the tires
小心点
Careful
我们向来都很小心  阿姨
We're always careful, ma'am
弟弟  你来发动
OK, little brother, you get the motor going
我来开
And I'll drive
能换个位置吗
Can we switch places?
太可爱了吧  但你太矮了
That's cute, but you're not tall enough
没办法控制方向
to work the controls
使劲拉一下吧
Now give her a good tug
好  随便你
All right, whatever
没事吧
Are you OK?
你应该要小心才对
You were supposed to be careful
修剪得还不错  吧
Nice work, I think
送你们亮晶晶的半毛钱吧
Here's a shiny nickel, boys
搞得这么乱还付什么钱
You're paying for this mess?
别宠他们了  玛丽
Quit spoiling them, Mary
半毛钱打发谁呢
A lousy nickel?
你这老不死
Why, you decrepit--
我们发财了
We're rich
接下来要去垃圾场
OK, next, we're going to head down to the junkyard
玩金属粉碎机
and play with the metal shredder
不要
No way
我已经受够你的折磨活动了
I've had it with your torturous activities
我
I'm--
等一下
wait a second
这什么地方
Where are we?
就在小丑学院旁边
Right by the Clown College
踩香蕉皮滑倒可恶学校
咋了
Why?
必须马上走开
We have to get out of here right now
快点
Come on
绕远路回家去
We'll take the long way home
怎么了
What's the matter?
你该不会怕小丑吧
You're not afraid of clowns, are you?
我不是早就告诉过你
I thought I told you
别过来了吗  小虾米
not to come around here, Shrimp
对啊
Yeah
你应该很早就提过了  吱吱哥
you might have mentioned that before, Squeakers
叫我吱吱先生
That's Mr. Squeakers to you
看来我的大鞋今天要踩个小痞子了
Looks like my big shoes get to stomp a tiny punk today
弟弟
Brother
不要
No
你
You--
你从那个大脚小丑脚下救了我
you saved me from that big-footed buffoon
那当然了
Of course
兄弟间要互帮互助
Brothers stick up for each other
我居然会这么说
I can't believe I'm saying this
但是
but, uh
我想多陪着你一起做事  哥哥
I think I want to do more stuff with you, big brother
饼干
动物园
那朵云像大象鱼
That cloud looks like an elephant fish
那朵云像刑具
That one looks like an iron maiden
那朵云像小水母
That one looks like a baby jellyfish
那朵云像深水炸弹
That one looks like a depth charge
谢谢海绵宝宝
Thank you, SpongeBob
让我今天这么美好
for a truly wonderful day
我从小就有很多兄弟姐妹
I had a lot of brothers and sisters growing up
但是对我好的一个都没有
but never one who was actually nice to me
弟弟  我准备好了
Little brother, I'm ready
好了
Ready?
准备好什么了
Ready for what?
我们现在是真兄弟了
We're real brothers now
我准备好要分享
I'm ready to share
我最深最秘密的秘密了
my deepest, most secretest secret
我发誓过绝不告诉任何人
I swore I'd never tell it to anyone
可我很紧张
But I'm nervous
你能先分享吗
Could you go first?
那当然了
Of course
能给我哥做啥事都行
Anything for my brother
我之所以外表蛮横
I put on a gruff exterior
是因为不想让世界伤害我
because I don't want the world to hurt me
但内心深处
But deep down
我却害怕会赶跑大家  从此无依无靠
I'm afraid I'll push everyone away and end up alone
太谢谢你分享了  弟弟
Well, thanks very much for sharing that, little brother
现在到我了
Now it's my turn
虽然谁都不应该知道的  但是
No one is supposed to know this, but--
但是
but--
是啥
Yes?
我的领带  是
My tie, it's--
别上去的
a clip-on
我就知道
I knew it
等等  什么
Wait, what?
我从来就没学会系领带
I never learned how to tie a tie
你看看
Look at it
亲眼看看我这可憎的耻辱
Look your eyes upon my accursed shame
心里话发泄出来就好受多了
Sure felt good to get that off my chest
就这样
That's it?
你秘密就这样吗
That's your secret?
开什么玩笑
Are you kidding me?
对  秘密就那样
Yep, that was it
等等  你不高兴吗
Wait, are you upset?
当然不高兴了
You're darn right I am
你应该得把秘密配方告诉我的
You were supposed to tell me the secret formula
才不会有谁理你那个领带
Nobody cares about your tie
秘密配方
The secret formula?
你想听那个啊
That's what you wanted to hear?
那可不能分享
I can't share that
都锁我大脑保险箱里了
It's locked in my brain box
那我就用这把钥匙开锁
Well, then, I'll use this key to unlock it
天啊  就怕会有这种事
Oh, boy, I was afraid of this
看来你俩天生不适合当兄弟
It looks like you two just weren't made to be brothers
真可惜
Such a shame
你们干什么
What are you doing?
负责任的家长唯一会做的事
Well, the only thing responsible parents can do--
让自家的孩子变成别家的问题
making our child someone else's problem
再见  痞老板
Bye, Plankton
我真的很喜欢有你当弟弟
I really liked having you as a brother
那我就每分每秒都恨
Yeah, well, I hated every minute--
你看啊  塞西尔
Why, look, Cecil
是个小男孩
It's a baby boy
太棒了
Fantastic
我一直都想给我们儿子来个弟弟
I've always wanted our son to have a brother
派大星
Oh, Patrick
好啊
All right
来下跳棋吧
Let's play checkers
跳棋
Checkers
真是兄弟
Oh, brother